[
    { "question" : "būt", "answer" : "to be", "pronunciation" : "/but/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "darīt", "answer" : "to do", "pronunciation" : "/da-riht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dot", "answer" : "to give", "pronunciation" : "/doht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dzīvot", "answer" : "to live", "pronunciation" : "/dzhee-voht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "domāt", "answer" : "to think", "pronunciation" : "/do-maht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "redzēt", "answer" : "to see", "pronunciation" : "/rehd-zet/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "iet", "answer" : "to go", "pronunciation" : "/yeh-t/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "vēlēties", "answer" : "to want", "pronunciation" : "/veh-ley-ties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "lasīt", "answer" : "to read", "pronunciation" : "/la-seeht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "runāt", "answer" : "to speak", "pronunciation" : "/roo-naht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "zināt", "answer" : "to know", "pronunciation" : "/zee-naht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "atcerēties", "answer" : "to remember", "pronunciation" : "/aht-tseh-reh-ties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "skatīties", "answer" : "to watch", "pronunciation" : "/skah-tihties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "justies", "answer" : "to feel", "pronunciation" : "/yoos-tiehs/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "sākt", "answer" : "to start", "pronunciation" : "/saakt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "pateikt", "answer" : "to say", "pronunciation" : "/pa-teykt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "atrast", "answer" : "to find", "pronunciation" : "/a-trahst/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "meklēt", "answer" : "to search", "pronunciation" : "/mehkleht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "vēlēt", "answer" : "to wish", "pronunciation" : "/veh-leyt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "spēlēt", "answer" : "to play", "pronunciation" : "/speh-leyt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "piedāvāt", "answer" : "to offer", "pronunciation" : "/pee-eh-daa-vaat/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "skriet", "answer" : "to run", "pronunciation" : "/skryet/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "jautāt", "answer" : "to ask", "pronunciation" : "/yow-taaht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "vērsties", "answer" : "to turn", "pronunciation" : "/vehr-sties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "izvēlēties", "answer" : "to choose", "pronunciation" : "/eez-veh-ley-ties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "palikt", "answer" : "to stay", "pronunciation" : "/pah-likt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "redzēties", "answer" : "to meet", "pronunciation" : "/rehd-zehties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "izskatīties", "answer" : "to look", "pronunciation" : "/eeks-ka-tihties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "klausīties", "answer" : "to listen", "pronunciation" : "/klau-seehties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "baidīties", "answer" : "to be afraid", "pronunciation" : "/ba-i-dihties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dzirdēt", "answer" : "to hear", "pronunciation" : "/dzir-deht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "saprast", "answer" : "to understand", "pronunciation" : "/sa-prahst/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "sagaidīt", "answer" : "to expect", "pronunciation" : "/sa-gai-diht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "mācīties", "answer" : "to learn", "pronunciation" : "/maa-tsih-ties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dzīvoties", "answer" : "to live", "pronunciation" : "/dzhee-vohties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "zvanīt", "answer" : "to call", "pronunciation" : "/zva-niht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "lasīties", "answer" : "to be read", "pronunciation" : "/la-sihties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "strādāt", "answer" : "to work", "pronunciation" : "/straa-daht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "stāvēt", "answer" : "to stand", "pronunciation" : "/staaveht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "pārvietoties", "answer" : "to move", "pronunciation" : "/paar-vye-toh-ties/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "braukt", "answer" : "to drive", "pronunciation" : "/brauhkt/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "atstāt", "answer" : "to leave", "pronunciation" : "/aht-staht/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "laiks", "answer" : "time", "pronunciation" : "/laɪks/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "cilvēks", "answer" : "person", "pronunciation" : "/t͡sɪlveːks/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "dzīvnieks", "answer" : "animal", "pronunciation" : "/d͡ziːvɲeːks/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "māja", "answer" : "house", "pronunciation" : "/maːja/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "auto", "answer" : "car", "pronunciation" : "/auto/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "zeme", "answer" : "land", "pronunciation" : "/zeme/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "skola", "answer" : "school", "pronunciation" : "/skoːla/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "nauda", "answer" : "money", "pronunciation" : "/naʊda/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "darbs", "answer" : "work", "pronunciation" : "/darps/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "māte", "answer" : "mother", "pronunciation" : "/maːte/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "tēvs", "answer" : "father", "pronunciation" : "/teːvs/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "bērns", "answer" : "child", "pronunciation" : "/beːrns/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "valsts", "answer" : "country", "pronunciation" : "/valsts/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "brālis", "answer" : "brother", "pronunciation" : "/braːlis/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "māsa", "answer" : "sister", "pronunciation" : "/maːsa/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "draugs", "answer" : "friend", "pronunciation" : "/draʊks/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "problēma", "answer" : "problem", "pronunciation" : "/probleːma/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "sirds", "answer" : "heart", "pronunciation" : "/sirds/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "roka", "answer" : "hand", "pronunciation" : "/roka/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "acs", "answer" : "eye", "pronunciation" : "/ats/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "auss", "answer" : "ear", "pronunciation" : "/aus/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "deguns", "answer" : "nose", "pronunciation" : "/deguns/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mute", "answer" : "mouth", "pronunciation" : "/mute/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "zobs", "answer" : "tooth", "pronunciation" : "/zobs/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "galva", "answer" : "head", "pronunciation" : "/galva/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mugura", "answer" : "back", "pronunciation" : "/mugura/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "krēsls", "answer" : "chair", "pronunciation" : "/kreːsls/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "galds", "answer" : "table", "pronunciation" : "/ɡalds/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "dators", "answer" : "computer", "pronunciation" : "/dators/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "telefons", "answer" : "telephone", "pronunciation" : "/telefons/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "ceļš", "answer" : "road", "pronunciation" : "/t͡seɫʃ/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "iela", "answer" : "street", "pronunciation" : "/ieːla/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pilsēta", "answer" : "city", "pronunciation" : "/piɫseːta/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "valoda", "answer" : "language", "pronunciation" : "/vaɫoda/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "grāmata", "answer" : "book", "pronunciation" : "/ɡraːmata/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "žurnāls", "answer" : "magazine", "pronunciation" : "/ʒurnaːɫs/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "zināšanas", "answer" : "knowledge", "pronunciation" : "/zinaːʃanas/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "darījums", "answer" : "deal", "pronunciation" : "/darjiːjums/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "uzņēmums", "answer" : "company", "pronunciation" : "/uzɲeːmums/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "dzīvoklis", "answer" : "apartment", "pronunciation" : "/d͡ziːvoplis/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pusdienlaiks", "answer" : "lunchtime", "pronunciation" : "/pusdienlaɪks/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pusnakts", "answer" : "midnight", "pronunciation" : "/pusnacts/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pusdienas", "answer" : "lunch", "pronunciation" : "/pusdienas/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "vakariņas", "answer" : "dinner", "pronunciation" : "/vakariɲas/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pusdienošana", "answer" : "lunch break", "pronunciation" : "/pusdienoʃana/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "brīvdiena", "answer" : "day off", "pronunciation" : "/briːvdiena/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "iepirkšanās", "answer" : "shopping", "pronunciation" : "/iepirkʃanaːs/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pasākums", "answer" : "event", "pronunciation" : "/pasaːkums/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "liels", "answer" : "big", "pronunciation" : "/liɛls/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "mazs", "answer" : "small", "pronunciation" : "/mazs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "labāks", "answer" : "better", "pronunciation" : "/labɑːks/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "sliktāks", "answer" : "worse", "pronunciation" : "/sliktɑːks/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "vecs", "answer" : "old", "pronunciation" : "/vɛts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "jauns", "answer" : "young", "pronunciation" : "/jauns/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "labs", "answer" : "good", "pronunciation" : "/lɑbs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "slikts", "answer" : "bad", "pronunciation" : "/slikt͡s/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "tīrs", "answer" : "clean", "pronunciation" : "/tiːrs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "netīrs", "answer" : "dirty", "pronunciation" : "/nɛtiːrs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "silts", "answer" : "warm", "pronunciation" : "/sils/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "auksts", "answer" : "cold", "pronunciation" : "/auksts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "gaišs", "answer" : "light", "pronunciation" : "/ɡaiʃs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "tumšs", "answer" : "dark", "pronunciation" : "/tumʃs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "skaists", "answer" : "beautiful", "pronunciation" : "/skai̯sts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "neglīts", "answer" : "ugly", "pronunciation" : "/nɛɡliːts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "vēlēšanās", "answer" : "willing", "pronunciation" : "/veːlɛːʃanas/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "apmierināts", "answer" : "satisfied", "pronunciation" : "/apmiɛrinaːts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "dusmīgs", "answer" : "angry", "pronunciation" : "/dusmiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "laimīgs", "answer" : "happy", "pronunciation" : "/laimiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "nopietns", "answer" : "serious", "pronunciation" : "/nopiɛtns/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "izklaidējošs", "answer" : "entertaining", "pronunciation" : "/izklai̯dɛːjoʃs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "atvērts", "answer" : "open", "pronunciation" : "/atvɛːrts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "slēgts", "answer" : "closed", "pronunciation" : "/sleːɡts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "skaļš", "answer" : "loud", "pronunciation" : "/skalʃs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "kluss", "answer" : "quiet", "pronunciation" : "/klus/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "ātrs", "answer" : "fast", "pronunciation" : "/aːtrs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "lēns", "answer" : "slow", "pronunciation" : "/leːns/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "grūts", "answer" : "hard", "pronunciation" : "/ɡruːts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "viegls", "answer" : "easy", "pronunciation" : "/viɛɡls/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "garšīgs", "answer" : "tasty", "pronunciation" : "/ɡarʃiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "bezgaršīgs", "answer" : "tasteless", "pronunciation" : "/bɛzɡarʃiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "veselīgs", "answer" : "healthy", "pronunciation" : "/vɛsɛliːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "neveselīgs", "answer" : "unhealthy", "pronunciation" : "/nɛvɛsɛliːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "sarežģīts", "answer" : "complicated", "pronunciation" : "/sarɛzɡɡiːts/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "vienkāršs", "answer" : "simple", "pronunciation" : "/viɛnkaːrʃs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "izpratīgs", "answer" : "understanding", "pronunciation" : "/izpratiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "neizpratīgs", "answer" : "incomprehensible", "pronunciation" : "/nɛizpratiːɡs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "skaidrs", "answer" : "clear", "pronunciation" : "/skai̯d̪rs/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "ātri", "answer" : "quickly", "pronunciation" : "/aːtri/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "lēnām", "answer" : "slowly", "pronunciation" : "/leːnaːm/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "labi", "answer" : "well", "pronunciation" : "/labi/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "slikti", "answer" : "badly", "pronunciation" : "/slikti/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "vienmēr", "answer" : "always", "pronunciation" : "/viɛnmeːr/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "reti", "answer" : "rarely", "pronunciation" : "/rɛti/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "dažreiz", "answer" : "sometimes", "pronunciation" : "/dazrɛiz/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "tur", "answer" : "there", "pronunciation" : "/tur/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "šeit", "answer" : "here", "pronunciation" : "/ʃɛit/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "mazliet", "answer" : "a little", "pronunciation" : "/mazliɛt/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "ļoti", "answer" : "very", "pronunciation" : "/ʎoti/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "vispār", "answer" : "at all", "pronunciation" : "/vispaːr/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "tāpat", "answer" : "likewise", "pronunciation" : "/taːpat/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "tikai", "answer" : "only", "pronunciation" : "/tikai/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "jau", "answer" : "already", "pronunciation" : "/jau/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "vēl", "answer" : "still", "pronunciation" : "/veːl/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "tiešām", "answer" : "really", "pronunciation" : "/tiɛʃaːm/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "iespējams", "answer" : "possibly", "pronunciation" : "/iɛspeːjams/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "noteikti", "answer" : "definitely", "pronunciation" : "/notɛikti/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "katru reizi", "answer" : "every time", "pronunciation" : "/katru reizi/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" }
]